# mohamed mahmoud

Hadaeq Al Qubbah, Cairo-Egypt



in linkedin.com/in/mohamed-mahmoud-19ab47122



https://mohamedjs.herokupp.com



mohammed\_hs55@yahoo.com



**%** 01102693822

# Summary

I'm a Self-Taught Full-Stack Web Developer who prefers to work as a Back-end Developer,

I have been in the web development field for more than 4 years, got my first project 3 years ago, decided to focus on backend development especially for Laravel and Vuejs 3 year ago after learning a lot of web technology in backend as well as frontend,

now I'm familiar with many web technologies like Python, nodejs, c++, but specialized in Laravel, Vuejs, and their sidekicks

# **Experience**



#### Full Stack Developer

**iVAS** 

Jan 2019 - Present (1 year 6 months +)

- Write clean, secure, test driven, easily maintainable and modular code and use some design pattern to increase project performance and to make project easy scalable.
- Troubleshoot and debug applications.
- Act as technical lead in some project in the last 5 month.
- Perform UI / backend tests to optimize performance.
- Collaborate and work with frontend and mobile app developers on the backend needs of projects.
- Collaborate with team
- Client communication (verbal/written) as and when required
- Utilize backend data services and contribute to increase existing data services API
- · Lead the entire web application development life cycle right from concept stage to delivery and post launch support

#### Full Time Back End Developer

#### Grand

Jun 2018 - Dec 2018 (7 months)

- Client communication (verbal/written) as and when required
- Utilize backend data services and contribute to increase existing data services API
- Collaborate and work with frontend and mobile app developers on the backend needs of projects.
- · Lead the entire web application development life cycle right from concept stage to delivery and post launch support



### Full Time Back End Developer

LoadServ For Integrated Business Solution

Jan 2018 - May 2018 (5 months)

- Collaborate and work with a team and develop myself to learn new technical.
- Help team to solve complex problem and collaborate with them.
- In some project take front end problem and work in it to improve my self in front end technology
- · Lead the entire web application development life cycle right from concept stage to delivery and

post launch support

# ■ Training Back End Developer

## Faggala Start Up, Smart Villages

Aug 2017 - Sep 2017 (2 months)

- Learn how to work with Agile methods especially with scrum
- Learn how to work with OpenCart Cms to make system
- Learn how to search and how to be self-study



# lntern

#### Innova Egypt

Jul 2017 - Jul 2017 (1 month)

- Innova is a leader in transforming Revolutionary ideas into products and quickly adopted in your home and office
- Designing and developing innovative products and systems to improve the quality of life both in corporate buildings and residential
- Learn how to make your startup and the lifecycle for taking your product to Light

#### Education



### **Helwan University Cairo**

Bachelor's degree, Computer and Information Sciences, General 2014 - 2018

#### **Licenses & Certifications**



**CCNA** 

### **Skills**

Laravel • Vue.js • Data Structures • Algorithms • C++ • HTML5 • Design Patterns • SQL • Python (Programming Language) • Node.js